

70/D, West Dhanmondi Shankar, Dhaka-1207, Bangladesh

☑ ovipaulcs@gmail.com | 🌴 ovipaul.github.io | ᡚ ovipaul | 🛅 ovipaul

Summary

Highly motivated and passionate about Data Science and Software Engineering. My goal is to use my skills in machine learning, computer vision and statistical analysis to build software that will solve real-world problems. Firmly believe, experiences will help me to work as a competent engineer in the future.

Work Experience _____

Artificial Intelligence and Cybernetics Lab

Dhaka, Bangladesh

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Feb. 2020 - Present

- · Working with state of the art Deep Learning models, analyzing the whole architecture and finding ways to to optimize the system to obtain better result.
- Creating and collecting data along with developing the pre-processing and post-processing.
- Creating pipelines for the whole procedure and doing continuous integration and maintenance.
- Staying up-to date with recent publications of the relevant field.
- Writing scientific papers and documentations.

Independent University, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Apr. 2016 - Dec. 2019

TEACHING ASSISTANT(TA)

- · CSC101 Introduction to Programming.
- CSC204 Data Structure.
- CSC317 Numerical Method.

Skills

Language Python, Matlab, C++, Javascript **Frameworks** Pytorch, Electron, Bootstrap, Streamlit **GIS Tools** QGIS, eCognition, SNAP, ArcGIS Other Tools Latex, Git, Anaconda, SCP, SSH

Publications

2020	Proceedings , A Novel Disaster Image Data-set and Characteristics Analysis	ICPR
2020	Conference Paper, Deep-learning coupled with novel categorization method to classify the urban	ICRSFTF
	environment of the developing world	TCNSETE
2019	Book Chapter, LULC Segmentation of RGB Satellite Image Using FCN-8	SLAAI
2018	Conference Paper, Image Pre-processing on NumtaDB for Bengali Handwritten Digit Recognition	ICBSLP

Honors & Awards

2018	Winner, Intra IUB Programming Contest	IEEE
2018	Regional Qualifiers, ICPC Asia Dhaka Regional Contest	ACM
2018	Regional Qualifiers, ICPC Bangladesh IUBAT NCPC	ACM
2017	Winner, IEEE Day Programming Contest 2017	IEEE

Education

Independent University, Bangladesh(IUB)

Dhaka, Bangladesh B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering

2015 - 2020

St. Joseph Higher Secondary School

Dhaka, Bangladesh

HIGHER SECONDARY EDUCATION IN SCIENCE

2012 - 2014